Donatus.
Poswell.
Linemile.
Johnny.
Colin.
Tony.
Willard.
Ripley.
Mechthild.
Meiyou.
I'm sorry... I need to use you.
Family Portrait
13 Years Ago
Why don't you just give them a pat?
They're your kids, aren't they?
I don't want them to become monsters like me.
Geez, if it were something you could "catch" like a cold, I would have become one a long time ago.
I've witnessed many deaths since gaining this body.
But I was able to suppress the sadness by telling myself that death is just a speck in the grand scheme of things.
Whenever I'd witness something beautiful or wondrous, I'd accept this body, thinking it'd give me time to see them all...
That's how it's always been for me.
Until I met you and had kids, Trisha.
I never age, but I'm watching
my kids age and grow like trees...
I'm terrified all of a sudden.
It reminds me that I truly am a monster.
Dear!
Dear, come here for a second!
What is it?
Good day, sir.
A photographer?
Try to look nice, now.
We've never taken a family portrait before, have we?
But this is so sudden...
Hold on to Ed.
Okay...
We're ready now.
Please take the picture.
I don't like this...
Face this way, please.
Don't move, okay?
You know... someday, I'll turn into a wrinkled old woman who looks like a monster.
But no matter how I end up looking, I'll always be happy to take a picture with the family where everyone is smiling.
So please... stay with your family.
Don't distance yourself from us and leave us alone.
Don't hurt yourself by saying you're a monster.
Okay! Say cheese!
Smile, Dear.
I was planning to accept this body and continue living like this.
But I've changed my mind.
I want to age and die with Trisha and the kids.
That bastard...
That should do it...
What were you doing up there?
Fixing the swing.
You're not really used to these things, are you?
I couldn't do a single thing for them, so I wanted to at least do this.
Trisha, I'm going.
Please wait for me.
Okay.
Don't tell the kids about my body.
Sure.
Don't you want to say goodbye to them?
If I see their faces, I'll...
You blockhead. It's okay if you cry.
H-Hey, why are you two up so early?
Al says he needs to go pee...
Oh, so you were looking after Al.
Thank you, Ed.
Just a bit longer.
Can't focus. My body is still puzzled about what to do.
Shuuchuu dekitenaina mada karada ga mayotteirunda
I'm trembling. I can't stop even if I try to control myself.
Furueteitanja kontoroorushitatte burerunda
Although neither sun nor moon are on my side,
Taiyou mo tsuki mo nanmo kanzen ni kocchi muiteinaiga
"I've no choice but to try,"
Yarushikanainda
Those were the words I muttered to myself.
Iikikaseruyouni sotto tsubuyaita
The odds aren't on my side, but running way'd be gutless.
Joukyou wa waruiga tada nigedasunja konjou nainaa
Even if I can't see the future, I'll just have to win it over with courage.
Tenbou wa naiga dokyou de kuria suru shika naiya
Need to keep distance from the target as I hold myself back.
Shoudou wa osaetamama taagetto to no kankaku sagure
All that's needed for victory is pride to win.
Hitsuyou na mon wa katsu puraido
Will we celebrate with the wine of victory
Ajiwau nowa shouri no bishu ka
Or'll we end up kissing their feet in defeat?
Soretomo haiboku no kujuu ka
There are two outcomes to everything.
Sou subete wa futatsu ni hitotsu
I want to control destiny.
Ayatsuritai unmei no ito
I need to seize the golden opportunity with my hands.
Zekkou no goorudentaimu kono te de tsukame
I'll finish it up with my best poker face,
Konshin no pookaafeisu kimete shikakeruyo
And drag them into a world of illusions.
Iryuujon no sekai e hikizurikonde
I'll find my way out of this endless pressure game,
Saigennai puresshaageemu sururito nukete
And leap over the borderline of honor.
Eikou no boodaarain tobikoeru tameni
How many? What'll I need to sacrifice to make it happen?
Haumenii? Dorekurai no daishou ga iru?
What is the one thing I don't want to let go?
Tebanashitakunai mon wa dore?
Any luck?
No, I still can't reach them.
This isn't good... we can't contact the guys at base.
What now? Should we keep going?
There should be an exit somewhere to toss the rubble that was dug out.
Let's keep going for just a bit.
Smith, you go back to report on the situation.
Roger!
What's wrong?
Spread out!
Are you interested in a perfect, immortal army?
He fell for it!
No death, no decay...
Aren't you interested?
I want to cut him to pieces!
It's just that the idea is so wild; I don't know how to respond.
There are only two choices:
You're either interested, or you're not.
I'm intrigued.
So when that day comes, not just I,
but my men will also be able to benefit from this?
When that day comes, yes.
So he can't guarantee that much, huh...
If I accept their offer, they'll force me to assist them in causing a bloodbath at Briggs.
And if I decline, they'll put someone else in charge of the base, and I'll most likely be demoted or reassigned.
Now, I wonder what my best option is...
Pardon me.
What is it?
I'm sorry to bother you, ma'am!
The advance unit that went into the underground tunnel-
What about the underground tunnel?
It's okay. Say it.
Roger.
Something has happened to them.
Understood. I'll be right there.
I'll go, too.
All right, let's move.
Hang on!
We'll need to be tied up, right?
What's all this, Buccaneer?
I'm currently transferring the Elric Brothers from the east cells to the west cells, sir!
Who is that gentleman, if I may ask?
Solf J. Kimblee.
He's Lieutenant General Raven's guest.
Kimblee... So he's the Crimson Alchemist.
The Elric Brothers... So you must be the Fullmetal Alchemist.
Now I see why you were given that name.
Oh... it's you.
It's been a while since anyone's made that mistake!
Nice to meet you, Fullmetal Alchemist.
Likewise.
General!
What happened?
We've lost contact with the platoon that went to investigate the tunnel.
And soon after, Smith's horse came back with an arm presumed to be his.
Just his arm?
What about his body?
Missing, ma'am.
The horse he was on is too worked up
and can no longer be used.
Henshel, send in a rescue party imme-
This isn't good, Major General Armstrong.
That hole is far too dangerous.
What did you do with that biological weapon you were talking to me about?
Put him back into the tunnel and
cover up the hole, Major General.
But our men are still-
I'm talking to the Major General.
Isn't that the law here?
Obey the ones with power, Major General Armstrong.
I'm Raven from Central.
I've heard everything from the Führer President.
Pleasure to meet you.
It seems you've been keeping your mouths shut.
We promised, after all.
You don't seem too happy.
Wouldn't it be strange to be happy after having people taken hostage?
Umm... when can we get out of here?
The deal was that we'd be able to continue
our journey as long as we didn't get in your way.
Don't worry, I'll get you out of here soon.
That hole... it's also a part of your plan, isn't it?
If they find out...
You don't need to worry about that, either.
Major General Armstrong agreed to returning
the Homunculus in the tunnel and sealing the hole.
The Major General joined forces with us, too.
General!
Aren't we going to search for the missing unit?
Silence, Henshel.
But they may still be alive and need assistance!
I said, silence!
Shut up and obey.
"Obey the ones with power", eh?
So even the impregnable "Northern Wall of Briggs" has to give in to authority.
Well, that's the smart approach to things.
Oh? So that's the...
Good morning, Sloth.
Did you sleep well?
Who are you?
I'm still sleepy...
Hey, now. You still have some work to do.
Didn't Pride tell you so?
Pride?
It's a drag... but I have to do it...
What a drag...
Why was it a drag again?
Trying to remember is a pain...
No need to worry.
He's a chimera that's performing a task for the Central Army.
He's working to make this country stronger.
But it's still a top-secret mission.
Now, cover up this hole, my friends at Briggs.
You all are kindred spirits who I've shared my secrets with!
The essential parts have been replaced with ancient Ishbalan, so I can't read it.
I guess we can't help that, huh...
If Scar were here, we might be able to figure it out.
If he's an Ishbalan monk, there's a chance he'd know the ancient language.
I wonder if something happened to Mr. Scar?
We've found her!
A little girl carrying a black and white cat!
Okay, let's move.
Mr. Scar! Sir Yoki!
Did you find the research documents?
Yes, we did!
Let's switch locations.
The soldiers from Briggs have already found this place.
Hurry.
A Few Days Later
This is fine.
We, the chosen ones, will be granted a body close to God's, and we'll rule this world.
Was his name Smith?
Nothing can be done about the advance unit.
So the weak should become victims for the chosen ones to survive?
That's right. Survival of the fittest.
The weak become the foundations of a nation, and the strong prosper above them.
So Ishbal was also...
That's right.
Ishbal was also a part of our plan.
Those weak people were destined to be destroyed.
I see.
Please leave that to me.
Yes, sir.
Sorry for the wait.
You certainly make a lot of phone calls, don't you?
Where is Lieutenant General Raven?
I have something to tell him.
You were on the verge of death, but you somehow managed to make a recovery on the same day.
What kind of magic spell did you use?
Don't worry about it.
And besides, you were jailed for killing officers. How did you manage to get out?
I told you, don't worry about it.
Since when has this plan been in motion?
I've heard it's been in motion since this country was created.
And it'll finally be complete during my generation.
I thank you for your cooperation, Major General Armstrong.
I'll negotiate with the higher-ups and prepare a seat for you.
No need.
What?
Was that Smith's left arm? Or his right?
W-What are you...
Aging is truly horrifying, isn't it, Lieutenant General Raven?
I'm sure you used to be a young, dignified soldier who loved this country from the bottom of his heart.
Y-You...
You have the chance to become a chosen one...
I promised you a seat...
There's no need for another seat.
I'll be taking the seat your rotten ass has been sitting on!
You useless geezer!!!
Immortality... is right in front of you...
You can lie there and literally become a foundation of this base, Lieutenant General Raven.
I wanted... to become immortal...
Buccaneer, contact Miles.
Yes, ma'am!
Everyone else, continue working as if nothing's happened!
General.
Thanks.
Smooth the concrete, got it?
Roger.
You're being very pushy.
Is it because I'm a State Alchemist who served in the Ishbalan War?
What can I do to satisfy you?
Do you want to know what kind of deaths your people experienced?
Shut up, Kimblee.
Don't you want to know?
I told you to shut up!
Do you have a moment, Major?
I have a message from Major General Armstrong.
She says, "Mission complete.
You don't need to buy any more time."
Roger.
Good grief.
Finally, I'm relieved from talking with that freak.
Even though I was putting on an act, it was exhausting.
Kimblee.
Apparently, Lieutenant General Raven is missing.
Do you happen to know where he'd be?
Missing?
This isn't good.
The base isn't built safely enough for people to just walk around.
If something happens to the Lieutenant General-
That's good for me.
I received permission from the Führer President to act independently if something happened to Lt. General Raven.
Could you drive me down to the base of the mountain, Major Miles?
Do you understand?
My orders right now hold equal importance to those of the Führer President's.
Please wait, General!
Before you cover the hole completely, please send in a search squad for Smith and the unit...
The Fullmetal Alchemist created a secret passage in case a situation like this arose.
She killed him?!
Lieutenant General Raven?!
Well, that's all I needed to tell you.
Hey! Wait!
When the hell are you guys going to let us out?!
Who knows? Ask the Major General.
Dammit...
Getting impatient won't do us any good, Brother.
It's more important to rest for now...
I can't stay put when so many things are going on!
Hey, how's it going?
I've come to speak with the Fullmetal Alchemist-
Oh? It seems as though I'm not very popular here.
I've brought a guest today for you two.
A guest?
You idiot!!!
Why did you come here?!
"Why"?!
To switch your automail to the kind they use up here, of course!
Why are you guys in jail, anyway?!
No one called you out here!
What the heck is your problem?
I was so worried about you!
I wouldn't have known if the people from the military hadn't told me about it!
The military?!
Come on, you two.
The Führer President was very worried to hear of the situation.
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
We used to talk all night until the sun rose,
Asahi ga noboru made katariattane
And held hands till the sun went under the horizon.
Yuuhi ga shizumu made tsunaida te
Let's walk together like this forever, like light and shadow.
Kouyatte asu mo asatte mo tomo ni ayumou hikari to kage
I stand in the city, staring off into space with lonely eyes.
Samishige ni mitsumeru machi no naka de
I can't find warmth on my own.
Nukumori wa hitori ja mitsukaranakute
By meeting you, I realized
Ai ga konnani tsuyosa ni narukoto
How much strength love could give me.
Shittanda kimi ni deaete hajimete
Even if we part and meet again, I want to meet at this place.
Megurimeguttemo mata koko de aitai
Then we'll hold hands to ensure we'll never be separated again.
Hagurenaiyouni kono te wo tsunagunda
I can't sleep by myself, 'cause I can't dream without you.
Hitori ja nemurenai yume wa mirenaikara
So take me to a place where uncertainty can't reach us
Donna fuan mo todokanai tokoro e
And let us bring light to the night sky with no stars.
Hoshi no yoru mo terashitsuzukeyou
So long as you're with me, I can go to world's end.
Doko made mo yukeru kimi to nara
Even if it's a path I can't walk on my own,
Hitori ja arukenai michi mo futari nara
If you're by my side, I can walk it while humming a tune.
Hanauta utainagara arukerunda
If we're together, the world is mine.
Kimi ga ireba shiawase
Kimblee?
Yeah.
I heard from a friend who works as a nurse at the foot of Briggs.
He was hospitalized with serious injuries,
but his wounds were healed right after Lieutenant General Raven came to visit, and he was released right away.
Raven and Kimblee...
That's about all the information I have for today.
Thanks.
I'll ask for your help again when I need it.
Stop by at the shop again, okay?
You were dumped, eh?
Why don't you buy some flowers and chase after her?
I know when to give up.
I'll pass.
There are women who will dump you, but there are also women who are looking for a match.
I have a message from
Major General Olivier Mira Armstrong,
Colonel Roy Mustang.
I'll be buying all of those flowers.
The chain binding them appears in unusual form.
Boy, unbind the chains and wrench them off.
Reel it in and expose the enemy.
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
The First Homunculus
Episode 37, The First Homunculus.
Stratagems and blackmailing.
Those are the measures taken to fulfill one's desires.